FROM THE PEN OF "THE CITADEL'S" BOLD AUTHOR!
The Stars Look Down is a drama film directed by Carol Reed.
Davey Fenwick leaves his mining village on a university scholarship intent on
returning to better support the miners against the owners.
But he falls in love with Jenny who gets him to marry her and return
home as local schoolteacher before finishing his degree.
Davey Fenwick, played by Michael Redgrave.
Jenny Sunley, played by Margaret Lockwood.
Joe Gowlan, played by Emlyn Williams.
Martha Fenwick - Davey's mother, played by Nancy Price.
Richard Barras - the mine owner, played by Allan Jeayes.
Robert Fenwick - Davey's father, played by Edward Rigby.
The Stars Look Down is a British film from 1940, based on A.
Cronin's 1935 novel of the same title, about injustices
in a mining town in North East England.
The film, co-scripted by Cronin and directed by Carol Reed, stars Michael
Redgrave as Davey Fenwick and Margaret Lockwood as Jenny Sunley.
The film is a New York Times Critics' Pick and is listed in The New
York Times Guide to the Best 1,000 Movies Ever Made.
The film explores themes of trade union, miner, social commentary, labor union.
The tone is emotional.